If you want to get through these tutorials twice as fast just click
the gear icon on the bottom right of the video and under
speed. You can adjust the speed anywhere from normal speed
all the way up to 2X.
Hi there, welcome back to another adzorics tutorial. My name
is Adam. And today we're gonna be learning how to create modular
Clips so that we can create a edits at
lightning speed. The idea with modular Clips
is that we have our roles. We've already
gone through and we've scrubbed everything we've taken all
of the fat out and we put them in a folder that we can use a
later date for multiple different edits. And if
we use these modular Clips with adsrx
templates, the possibilities are
absolutely endless to create multiple different assets
for our ads. Okay. So
let's take a look at modularizing a clip and jump into Premiere.
Okay. So the first thing that we're gonna do is we're
going to import our raw Clips. So we're going
to locate that in our Media Browser down here
and the bottom left hand corner. So I have a bunch of nine
by 16 vertical raw clips that
we shot and I'm just going to highlight these
and I'm going to drag that and just
Like that over to my project and then
drag that into the rose folder that
I've already created. So I just drop that down and as
we can see we have those raw files there. So
if I just move this across here, so as you can see, I already
have some files pre-named and I have
some other files that haven't got any names. So I'm going to
be taking multiple clips from those files. I'm
just going to rename those clips as and when I need
to if I just close that for a second drop down sequence and
find a nine by 16 sequence. Now,
if you haven't already created your own premade
sequences, please go and check out that tutorial
where I run you through making your own custom sequences
go up to our Roars and
let's just collapse that for a second and I'm
going to double click this. So what we want to do is
just try and speak this up and make it a nice clean clip.
I don't want the audio from this clip.
So I'm just gonna select this video icon here.
Video only and I'm going to drag that into
my timeline keep existing settings now
depending on the aspect ratio that
this was filmed in you may need to adjust the scale
for this. So just go over to effects controls
and then grab the scale and then just bring
that down. Okay, so 50% there and what
we have with is iPhone footage is you can
see all of the whites really really strong whites here. So
what I want to do is come over to the left here. I'm going to
highlight these clips. I'm going to right click I'm
gonna go up to modify then go to
interpret footage. Now if you come all the way down to
the bottom here, you see the color space override you just
want to twirl that on and then if you see this
drop down files here, we can change the color
space override to rec 709
or maybe even Rec 2020.
I like what 2020 looks pretty good and
then press okay. So just to have a little play with
those and
Which colors you like best so we
can see there's a lot of shaking of the camera reframing.
This is where I want the scene to start with the
money and the diaper already there. So I'm going
to just drag that to the end there. Let's
zoom in now. I'm gonna stop that there. I'm gonna
press C and press cut and we're going to press play again.
Scrub that back just as the money comes in, press cut
select that delete is Right clip Ripple.
Delete take it to where the hand comes out.
See cut.
And then just as the diaper comes in see we've got
lots of Dead Space here. We want to get this nice and
cleanly timed so then C V. Delete
right? Click Ripple delete. So I'm
just going to do that for the rest of the clip. We just
got a scene where the actress swipes the money off just there.
We're gonna press V. Delete.
Ripple delete
sorry if I just cut that there.
And then we get rid of that last bit of the clip. So this
is like a pain point shot saying that we
don't want the diapers. It's costing too much money really great
scroll stopper. Okay. So now we're gonna
do this jump cut right here highlight that and again, I'm
going to drag that in with only the
video not the audio rough takes at the beginning
here. So we're just gonna trim all of that out. There we go.
Just as she's putting our hand in see just delete
that. Let's zoom in here a little
bit just so that we've got a little bit more space to play with there we
go opens the drawer.
And there's a bit of space there. So I think I want
to cut there.
Just as she brings a hand in there we go.
there so right click Ripple delete
Nice nice and smooth. So then just
as she clicks. There we go, make a switch
to the panties in the drawer. So we just want to get the
last bit of that click. There we go. So just there
and we want to get that movement in the hand. So it really
sells that jump cut.
There we go. Cut there select this right?
Click Ripple. Delete.
Okay.
So just got that movement when you turn the
camera off, there's sometimes a little bit of shake at
the end of the clip. So we just want to trim that
last little bit off there. So let's look at that clip all the
way through.
opens the drawer
Snap
boom picks up the panties shows it to the camera.
And the clip finishes so that's a jump cut modularized clip.
Bring that into an edit. We just add like a
snap sound effect to that really sells the clip. This could be
a b-roll shot right here.
So she's just picking up the panties from the
drawer. So I'm just gonna get that and cut that.
V hold oat and then click and drag
that to the right and now
we've got a b-roll shot of just picking up the panties out the drawer
showing it to the camera. Right? So now we're gonna go on
to a b-roll shot. I'm not
gonna bring the audio in with this. Yeah. She just
walks into the scene there. So we got a little bit of space at the
beginning just as she's about to walk in. Okay, there we
go. She walks into the scene drops the pads into the bin and
just as she walks out and the bin closes
boom trim off that end fat. So that's
another b-roll shot. Nice quick and simple. Okay. So
now we're going to select this clip here drag into
the timeline or we can play this
through in the top window here, which is what I like to
do. So, I'm just gonna press play.
all be disappointed I prom
ISE, okay, so she just missed the shot there the panties
didn't quite hit the camera lens real great
fun. So I'm pretty sure the last take here
is going to be the best one. So let's take a look
at this.
We can use this handle here to zoom
in.
And then we can drag here to just get to the start of her
talking. You can press I or you can just click this
button right here. So just as it hits the camera
lens just about there. I guess select the
out point you can have a press. Oh or you can select the
mark out Point button here. Okay. So now
I'm gonna select that clip and I'm
gonna drag that in just the framing
on this we can maybe just zoom in Just a
Touch Center her a little there we
go and then
You won't be disappointed. I promise that could
be the end of your ad. Okay, so now let's
look at how we can modularize a testimonial so
just as she starts.
I'm gonna press I for in point
then press play.
So I'm gonna select the out point there. We'll press
o and I'm going to drag that in and we're
gonna play that through.
After I had my first baby nobody talked about there's
a little pause there.
I'm gonna press C. So just before she
moves her eyes. There we go.
V
Right. Click Ripple. Delete
Again, there's another space.
see
just before she starts the next word.
V right click
Ripple delete
okay, and then let's play that through.
So what I would probably do is add some Crossfade effects
on this audio just to remove some audio
popping that you might hear. So I'm gonna go over
to effects. I'm gonna go to audio transitions cross
Fades now, we can select constant gain
or exponential fade. So let's give
that a shot and try that fudge. Just zoom in
here. You can see that so we can make that larger
or smaller. You want to keep that as small as possible.
Okay, that doesn't sound too bad
at all or what you could also do is select all of
the clips and press control shift d and
we see that we now have a Crossfade
there. So that's a modularized line
of a clip.
Nice tight lines now. If we go back over to our source
monitor, we could find the next line.
Okay, just at the end of there you're gonna bring that in again
come over and then do the similar sort
of thing, right? Okay, so I'm gonna do the same here control shift key
applies that fade just to make
sure that there's no pops.
Perfect. Okay. So now we have
a bunch of modularized Clips. You could go
through that entire testimonial and take out all of the separate lines.
And then you've got multiple different lines that you
can use in multiple different ads. So if I
just zoom in here and I'm gonna highlight all of my
cuts now, I'm gonna right click I'm gonna come
up to make subsequence and now we've
made a subsequence here. So what I can also do
here is then go to new bin
down in the bottom left-hand Corner, we're gonna
select that and we're gonna type
Subsequence. So now we've got subsequence and
we're just gonna drag that in there and I'm gonna highlight that
subsequence. So every time we make a subsequence
now that's highlighted. They're going to drop into that
folder. Okay. So we're just going to call this diapers costs
money. Now, we have a modularized clip in a subsequence.
So I'm going to do the same for this one. So this is pads to
panties jump cut. Okay. So next we're gonna
select our subsequence folder and we're gonna highlight that
pads to panties.
And now we've just got that panties b-roll shot. Okay. So
we're gonna right click that make subsequence panties
draw b-roll pads in
the trash can so again right click make subsequence
this one here. So again, we want to name
it similar to what is said in the clip.
after I had my first baby nobody talked about the fact
that there could be
some highlight right-click subsequence. Okay. Nobody
talked about leakage. There we go. Okay, so
I called that scared to laugh cough needed pads.
Okay, so if experience leakage try design
Comfort boom, okay, give yourself
a break try today simple simple and
easy. So the next thing to do is to export these so I'm
just gonna select this first one here and I'm
going to right click then select export media.
Okay, so that's gonna bring up the export window and
we have already had it named. So what we could
do is just if I just go up a folder we can see we've got the
rules folder and we've got the modularized clips folder.
So I'm just gonna select that modularized clips and I'm
going to click save because we already have
the named.
Okay. Now what we can do is just press export right
now and that will export it directly within Premiere
or if you have a full Adobe Creative
Cloud account. I would recommend downloading media
encoder. Okay. So what
we're gonna do is do that via media encoder and we're gonna select queue.
So what that's gonna do is bring up media encoder and place that in there.
So now that you've done that first one you've selected
that destination folder, you know where that's gonna
go. So we're just gonna minimize that and now we're
gonna come all the way over to the rest of these and we're going to highlight all
of these and then right click
then select export media. Now, you can
see it brings up a slightly different window here and you
can see that you can't select the destination folder. This is
the reason why we selected that destination folder
on that first clip. So now all we do
is we select queue and it's going to send all of these over
to Media encodile. We just
open up media and Coda. There we go. We can see that that
goes to modularized Clips because we please
selected that first clip. Okay. So now
I'm just gonna press play that will render all of those out.
Okay, so now they're all exported. All we
need to do is just click that folder here.
Okay. So now if I minimize that we now
have multiple different clips that we can use in
multiple different edits. We can combine them with our
templates.
And create new ads. They're ready
to rock. They're ready to go right there. And then enjoy making
new modularized clips. Enjoy having fun
making multiple different ads be creative. Have
fun. And remember guys. If you have any issues of
any of our templates, please get in touch with us, and we
will get back to you and try to fix those as soon as possible.
Thank you so much for watching and I will see you in the
next tutorial.